Indiana University Division of Biological Sciences records, 1906-1988 C85
Indiana University Archives
Indiana University Division of Biological Sciences records
1906-1988
Indiana University Archives
Indiana University, Bloomington. Division of Biological Sciences
C85
15.2 cubic feet
Collection consists of 15 cubic feet of records from the departments under the Division of Biological Sciences spanning 1906-1988. The records are organized in a single series, Subject files. Because the records were in great disarray and the original order was unknown, it was decided it was best to simply arrange the records alphabetically rather than attempt to separate out the various departments. Even so, the collection provides a wealth of information on scientific studies at Indiana University, as the collection consists of correspondence, reports, committee files and more, some dating prior to the development of the Division. For more information on the name changes of the departments, see the finding aid for the collection.
Access Restrictions
This collection is open for research. Advance notice is required.
Administrative History
The first courses in biology at Indiana University were offered in 1853-54. However, as early as 1828 John Harney was appointed to teach mathematics and "such of the natural sciences as were considered of sufficient importance to engage the attention of aspiring youth." Textbooks of the day covering "the natural sciences" dealt with such areas of biology as anatomy, some physiology, some biogeography, and much systematics.
During the early years of Indiana University, biology existed as a subset of the Natural Sciences, often in the form of zoological, botanical, or geological research. For example, Richard Owen, Prof. of Natural Philosophy and Chemistry (1864-1879) concentrated chiefly on geological studies, but extensively employed zoology and botany as part of his teaching. By 1869-70, zoology and botany appear as separate courses under Natural Sciences.
In 1879, David Starr Jordan assumed the post of Prof. of Natural Sciences and proceeded to expand and modernize the curriculum. In 1885, Jordan became president of Indiana University. Among his first official acts was the establishment of a Department of Zoology (chaired by Jordan himself) and a Department of Botany and Geology (chaired by John C. Branner). In 1891, Carl H. Eigenmann assumed control of the Department of Zoology. Among his many contributions to the department was the establishment of a Biological Station on Turkey Lake (now Wawasee) and the assembly of a distinguished faculty that included Will Scott, Fernandus Payne, and Alfred C. Kinsey. By this time, anatomy and physiology had drifted away following a separate course correlated with the medical program. Bacteriology was established as a separate department under Leland McClung and included such notable faculty as Salvador E. Luria (later Noble Laureate).
By the 1960s it was becoming increasingly evident that the biological sciences of the day were extending far beyond the issues covered in the isolated departments of Zoology, Botany, and Bacteriology. In 1963, the Indiana University Board of Trustees created the Division of Biological Sciences, comprised of the departments of Anatomy and Physiology, Botany, Microbiology, and Zoology. Tracey Sonneborn served as chair of the executive committee of the Division. Under the divisional organization, the various departments sought to create a variety of courses and programs designed to integrate the field of biology.
In 1977 it was decided to completely integrate the departments into a single Department of Biology in order to foster interdisciplinary research, pool resources and equipment, and create an atmosphere in which the different biological fields "worked together rather than against each other." Interesting sections within the department were created, including botany, cell and developmental biology, ecology, genetics, microbiology, molecular biology, and physiology and biochemistry. John Preer became the department's first chair.
Breakdown of department name changes:
Dept. of Anatomy and Physiology
Dept. of Bacteriology
Dept. of Botany
Dept. of Zoology
1966 Dept. of Bacteriology changes to Dept. of Microbiology
1972 Dept. of Botany changes to Dept. of Plant Sciences
1976 Dept. of Anatomy and Physiology transfers from the College of Arts and Sciences to the School of Medicine
1977 Depts. of Microbiology, Plant Sciences, and Zoology merge into a single Dept. of Biology
Arrangement
Indiana University Division of Biological Sciences records organized in a single series, Subject files, arranged alphabetically.
Scope and Content Note
In an attempt to maintain the original provenance of the collection, all files were organized in one large series, Subject files, and arranged in alphabetical order by folder title. The subject files include material concerning the administrative functions of the Division of Biological Sciences, the creation of a single Department of Biology, development of undergraduate and graduate courses, and scientific research conducted throughout the division and department by various faculty members including Noble prize winner, Hermann Muller.
Separated Material
All photographs and architectural plans have been removed from this collection. Please see a member of the archives staff for photographic images and architectural plans.
Acquisition Information
Accessions 5075-5085, 0428, 0196, 0281, 0090, 93/008, and 2010/096.
Provenance
The bulk of the collection (accessions 5075-5085, 0428, 0196, 0281, and 0090) were transferred by the Indiana University Department of Biology to the University Archives in 1978, 1984 and unknown dates.
Accession 93/008 was transferred by Charles W. Hagan in 1993.
The biological reports by W. R. Breneman (Accn. 2010/096) were receieved with the papers of Marvin Carmack in 2010.
Indiana University. Division of Biological Sciences; Indiana University. Department of Zoology; Indiana University, Bloomington. Department of Zoology; Indiana University. Department of Botany; Indiana University. Department of Plant Sciences; Indiana University, Bloomington. Department of Plant Sciences; Indiana University. Department of Bacteriology; Indiana University. Department of Microbiology; Indiana University, Bloomington. Department of Microbiology; Indiana University. Department of Anatomy and Physiology; Indiana University, Bloomington. Department of Anatomy and Physiology; Indiana University. Department of Zoology -- Archives; Indiana University, Bloomington. Division of Biological Sciences -- Archives; Indiana University, Bloomington. Department of Zoology -- Archives; Indiana University. Department of Botany -- Archives; Indiana University. Department of Plant Sciences -- Archives; Indiana University, Bloomington. Department of Plant Sciences -- Archives; Indiana University. Department of Bacteriology -- Archives; Indiana University. Department of Microbiology -- Archives; Indiana University, Bloomington. Department of Microbiology -- Archives; Indiana University. Department of Anatomy and Physiology -- Archives; Indiana University, Bloomington. Department of Anatomy and Physiology -- Archives
- Subject Files
  - A-General, 1948-1950 (Box 1)
  - A.B. Degree in Microbiology, undated (Box 1)
  - Academic Affairs, 1971-1973 (Box 1)
  - Academic Equipment, 1963-1975 (Box 1)
  - Academic Priorities Committee (Box 1)
    - General (Box 1)
      - 1970-1973 (Box 1)
      - 1973-1976 (Box 1)
    - 1st semester, 1972-1973 (Box 1)
    - 2nd semester, 1972-1973 (Box 1)
    - 1974-1975 (Box 1)
    - 1975-1976 (Box 1)
    - 1976-1977 (Box 1)
  - A-D, 1973-1977 (Box 1)
  - Adult Education And Public Services (Carmony), 1947-1959 (Box 1)
  - Affirmative Action Plan, undated (Box 1)
  - Afro-American Tutorial Program, 1969; undated (Box 1)
  - A-(General), 1973-1975 (Box 1)
  - Alumni Publications, 1957 (Box 1)
  - Department of Anatomy Physiology-Business (Box 1)
    - (Center for neural sciences) Jorgan Fex, 1972 (Box 1)
    - Alfred Strickholm, 1964-1975 (Box 1)
    - David Robertshaw, 1974-1975 (Box 1)
    - Emanuel M. Bogdanove, 1967 (Box 1)
    - Howard H. Rostorfer, 1971 (Box 1)
    - Ilsa Shwartz, 1974 (Box 1)
    - Roderick A. Suthers, 1966-1976 (Box 1)
    - Sherwin Mizell, 1976 (Box 1)
  - American Society Of Zoologists, Meeting In New Orleans, 1931 (Box 1)
  - Animal Care Advisory Committee, 1970-1972; undated (Box 1)
    General
    (old)
  - Animal Quarters, 1974-1977 (Box 1)
  - Annual Reports, 1967-1975 (Box 1)
  - Annual Report, 1967-1969 (Box 1)
  - Anti-Pesticide Responses, 1970-1973 (Box 1)
  - Arts And Sciences (Box 1)
    - (Ashton And Wagner), 1947-1949 (Box 1)
    - (Braden And Gucker), 1951-1961 (Box 1)
  - Assistant to Director-LRP, 1979-1980 (Box 1)
  - Associate Instructors, 1970-1976 (Box 1)
  - Atomic Energy Commission (Box 1)
    - (A.E.C.), 1956-1964 (Box 1)
    - Isotope Burials, 1962-1963 (Box 1)
    - License Muller-Lee Project, 1962-1963 (Box 1)
  - Audio-Visual Center (Larson), 1949-1963 (Box 1)
  - B-(General) (Box 1)
    - 1913-1958 (Box 1)
    - 1973-1975 (Box 1)
  - Bausch And Lomb, 1951 (Box 1)
  - BCCUC, 1974-1976 (Box 1)
  - Big Brother/Sisters Undergraduate Program, 1980 (Box 1)
  - Biochemistry Committee, 1958-1964 (Box 1)
  - Biochemistry Program, Interdepartmental Program, 1957-1964 (Box 1)
  - Bioengernetics Symposium, 1970-1972 (Box 1)
  - Biological Station (Box 1a)
    - (Winona Lake), 1950-1951 (Box 1a)
    - Brochure, 1970 (Box 1a)
    - Articles, Clippings, 1896-1904 (Box 1a)
    - Correspondence (Box 1a)
      - Bryan, William L., 1927-1932 (Box 1a)
      - Mannfield, George N., 1926-1930 (Box 1a)
      - Ortenburger, A.I., 1937 (Box 1a)
      - Scott, Will, 1927-1933 (Box 1a)
      - Smith, H.L., 1925-1931 (Box 1a)
    - Miscellaneous, 1926-1931 (Box 1a)
  - Biological reports, W. R. Breneman (Box 1a)
    - Nos. 1-3, 1959-1960 (Box 1a)
    - Nos. 4-6, 1960 (Box 1a)
  - Biology (Box 1a)
    - Brochure, 1970 (Box 1a)
    - Curriculum Faculty Comments, 1963-1973; undated (Box 2)
    - Exemption Exam Information, May 1974; undated (Box 2)
    - Graduates, 1976 (Box 2)
    - Library Committee, 1976-1977 (Box 2)
  - Biomedical Science Support Grant, 1970-1975 (Box 2)
  - Botany Department, 1963-1964 (Box 2)
  - Dean Briscoe (Dean Of Faculties), 1948-1952 (Box 2)
  - Bryan, WM. L. (President) (Box 2)
    - 1906-1920 (Box 2)
    - 1921-1926 (Box 2)
    - 1927-1930 (Box 2)
    - 1931-1933 (Box 2)
    - 1934-1936 (Box 2)
    - 1937 (Box 2)
    - -Dean Fernandus Payne's File, 1925-1945 (Box 2)
  - B.S. Degree in Microbiology, 1970-1977; undated (Box 2)
  - Budget Planning, 1967-1977; undated (Box 2)
  - Budgets, Departmental (Box 2)
    - 1941-1948 (Box 2)
    - 1949-1952 (Box 2)
    - 1953-1957 (Box 2)
  - Building, Space and Equipment Committee, 1963-1964; undated (Box 2)
  - Buildings And Grounds, 1950-1952 (Box 2)
  - Bulletins, 1963-1965 (Box 2)
  - C-(General), 1919-1976; 1930-1950 (Box 2)
    Arranged alphabetically
  - Catacean Symposium Proposal, 1975 (Box 2)
  - Centers of Excellence, 1965-1966 (Box 2)
  - Chairperson, 1973-1984 (Box 2)
  - Chancellors Office, 1971-1974 (Box 2)
  - Charter of the Division of Biological Science, 10/25/63, 1963; 1969; undated (Box 2)
  - Chemistry Department, Dec 1949 (Box 2)
  - Cleland, R.E., 4 Apr 1949 (Box 2)
  - Cole, Lamont C., 1946-1950 (Box 2)
  - College of Arts and Sciences (Box 2)
    - General, 1972-1977 (Box 2)
    - Bulletin, 1972-1976; undated (Box 2)
    - Curriculum Committee Minutes, 1972-1973 (Box 2)
  - Colleges and University Granting Degrees in Bacteriology or Microbiology, 1972; undated (Box 2)
  - Collins, Dean R.L. (Dean Of Faculty), 1948-1955 (Box 2)
  - DBS Committee on Curricula and Courses (Box 2)
    - 1963-1964 (Box 2)
    - Miscellaneous, 1968-1969 (Box 3)
    - 1969-1970 (Box 3)
    - 1970-1971 (Box 3)
    - 1971-1972 (Box 3)
    - Bulletin Revisions, 1969-1970 (Box 3)
    - Course Proposals, 1969-1970 (Box 3)
    - 1972-1975 (Box 3)
    - 1973-1974 (Box 3)
    - 1974-1975 (Box 3)
    - 1975-1976 (Box 3)
    - 1976-1977 (Box 3)
    - 1977-1978 (Box 3)
    - Course Proposals, 1968-1969 (Box 3)
    - Minutes, 1969-1973 (Box 3)
  - Committee for Future Studies, undated (Box 3)
  - Committee on Natural Areas, undated (Box 3)
  - Committee on Radiological Safety, undated (Box 3)
  - Committee I (Undergrad. Edu. in DBS & Appt. of Coordinator for Undergraduate Programs), undated; (2 folders) (Box 3)
  - Committee II of DBS (Box 3)
    - Report Ballots, undated (Box 3)
    - (Relationship of DBS Exec. Comm to faculty, etc.), undated (Box 3)
  - Committee III (Academic Priorities, New and Replacement Positions in DBS, etc.), undated (Box 3)
  - Committees in Dept. of Biology, undated (Box 3)
  - Computer-Assisted Instructional Programs for use in Biology, undated (Box 3)
  - Conservation Department--Indiana, undated (Box 3)
  - Consolidation of Biology, undated (Box 3)
  - Continuation Procedures for Graduate Students, undated (Box 3)
  - Correspondence, Miscellaneous, undated (Box 3)
  - Course (Box 3)
    - Approvals, 1970-1971 (Box 3)
    - Changes, undated (Box 3)
    - Development-DBS, undated (Box 3)
    - Development-Zoology, undated (Box 3)
    - DBS Course Information, undated (Box 3)
    - Outlines, undated (Box 3)
    - Reservation Plan, undated (Box 3)
    - Requests (Box 3)
      - 1969-1970 (Box 3)
      - 1970-1971 (Box 3)
    - DBS Course Requests-Approved, undated (Box 3)
  - Courses for Microbiology, undated (Box 3)
  - Crooked Lake (Box 3)
    - 1968 (Box 3)
    - Biological Station, 1969-1970 (Box 3)
  - Crowell, Sears, undated (Box 3)
  - CUEBS, undated (Box 3)
  - Curriculum, undated (Box 3)
  - Curriculum Committee (Box 3)
    - undated, (folder 1 of 2) (Box 3)
    - undated, (folder 2 of 2) (Box 4)
  - Curriculum-Graduate, undated (Box 4)
  - Curriculum Proposals, undated (Box 4)
  - Curriculum-Undergraduate, undated (Box 4)
  - "D", undated (Box 4)
  - Dean of Faculties, undated (Box 4)
  - Dean Of Students (Leo Dowling), undated (Box 4)
  - Dedication List, undated (Box 4)
  - Degree Program Proposals, undated (Box 4)
  - DeLanney, Louis, undated (Box 4)
  - Developmental Biology Committee, undated (Box 4)
  - Department of Microbiology-Business, undated (Box 4)
  - Departmental Review-Microbiology, undated (Box 4)
  - Department of Biological Sciences Ex. Comm. Minutes (Box 4)
    - 1963 (Box 4)
    - 1964 (Box 4)
    - 1965 (Box 4)
    - 1966 (Box 4)
    - 1967 (Box 4)
    - 1968 (Box 4)
    - 1969 (Box 4)
    - 1970 (Box 4)
    - 1/6/71-5/27/71 (Box 4)
    - 9/1/71-12/22/71 (Box 4)
    - 4/26/72- 11/30/72 (Box 4)
  - Director Division of Biological Sciences (Debate), 1963-1964 (Box 4)
  - Directories, undated (Box 4)
  - Division Of Biological Sciences Exec. Comm. (Box 4)
    - Minutes (Box 4)
      - 1/5/72-4/26/72 (Box 4)
      - 1972-1973 (Box 4)
    - Reports, 1977 (Box 4)
  - Division of Biological Sciences Professional Activities Reports, 1969-1973 (Box 5)
  - Division of Biological Services Plans, undated (Box 5)
  - DBS Undergraduate Educational Policies Committee(UEPC) (Box 5)
    - 1972 (Box 5)
    - 1973 (Box 5)
  - DBS Publications, 1969 (Box 5)
  - Report: DBS-The Next Ten Years, (undated 70's?) (Box 5)
  - Divisional Matters- Discussed in Conference with Dean Franz, June 10, 1976 (Box 5)
  - Division-Review of DBS by the College of Arts and Sciences (Box 5)
    - 1971 (Box 5)
    - 1974 (Box 5)
  - Division of Technical Studies, 1964-1965 (Box 5)
  - "E", undated (Box 5)
  - E-H, undated (Box 5)
  - Ebert, James D., undated (Box 5)
  - Ebert Lab Equipment Inventory, undated (Box 5)
  - Ecology, undated (Box 5)
  - Education Fellow in Academic Administration, undated (Box 5)
  - Educational Opportunity Fellowships, 1972-1973 (Box 5)
  - Educational Policies Committee (Box 5)
    - 1974-1975 (Box 5)
    - First Semester, 1975-1976 (Box 5)
    - Second Semester, 1975-1976 (Box 5)
    - First Semester, 1976-1977 (Box 5)
    - Second Semester, 1976-1977 (Box 5)
    - Report, 1968-1969 (Box 5)
    - Responses-Representation of Developmental Biology Faculty on EPC, undated (Box 5)
    - Responses-Representation or Organismal Biology Faculty on EPC, 1976 (Box 5)
    - Questionnaire in Organismal Diversity And Adaptation Course, 1975 (Box 5)
  - Eigenmann, Carl H.: Departmental Correspondence, 1914-1920 (Box 5)
  - Electron Microscope Committee, undated (Box 5)
  - DBS-Electron Microscope Technique B545 & B546, undated (Box 5)
  - Elliot, Dr. Peggy academic year) American Council on-, 1980-1981 (Box 5)
  - E Miscellaneous, undated (Box 5)
  - Enrollment (Box 5)
    - Data, undated (Box 5)
    - Reports, undated (Box 5)
  - Environmental Biology, undated (Box 5)
  - Environmental Health and Safety, undated (Box 5)
  - Equipment and Appliance Responses, April 1976 (Box 5)
  - Equipment Committee, undated (Box 5)
  - DBS-Equipment Proposal, undated (Box 5)
  - Exam Questions MA and PhD Degrees, undated (Box 5)
  - Executive Committee (Box 5)
    - 1966 (Box 5)
    - Meeting Minutes, undated (Box 5)
  - Extension Centers (Box 6)
    - 1969 (Box 6)
  - "F", 1930-1959; undated (Box 6)
  - F-(General), 1970-1973; undated (Box 6)
  - Faculty (Box 6)
    - General, 1967-1972; undated (Box 6)
    - Agenda Notes, 1973-1974 (Box 6)
    - Annual Report, 1967-1968 (Box 6)
    - Award Information, 1974-197 (Box 6)
    - Bibliography-Med Center, 1 Jul 1969- 30 Jun 1970 (Box 6)
    - Housing And Graduate Assistants, 1948; 1954-1955 (Box 6)
    - Meetings, 1968-1988 (Box 6)
    - Meeting Summaries (DBS), 1972-1973 (Box 6)
    - Microbiology, 1970-1976; undated (Box 6)
    - Teaching Assignments, 1972-1977; undated (Box 6)
    - Zoology Agenda Notes, 1971-1973 (Box 6)
  - Fee Remission, 18 Aug 1980 (Box 6)
  - Fee Remission and Reduction, 1971-1976 (Box 6)
  - Fellowship Committee Info., 1975-1976 (Box 6)
  - Fellowship Report, 1974 (Box 6)
  - Fellowships (Box 6)
    - 1948-1949 (Box 6)
    - 1973-1983 (Box 6)
  - Fish Collection, 1929-1931 (Box 6)
  - Floyd Scholarship, 1960-1976 (Box 6)
  - Floyd Summer Fellowship, 1980; 1984 (Box 6)
  - Foreign Language Requirement, 1972 (Box 6)
  - Foreign Language Tool Skill Requirements, 1974-1975; undated (Box 6)
  - Foreign Students-(General), 1970-1976; undated (Box 6)
  - Freshman Biology Committee, 1974-1975; undated (Box 6)
  - DBS Freshman Biology Committee-(Ad Hoc Committee on 100 level Courses), 1972-1976; undated (Box 6)
  - Frey, David G., 1950-1955; undated (Box 6)
  - Fringe Benefit Review Committee, 1981-1982 (Box 6)
  - Funding Study: Impact on Funding Policies, 1972-1980; undated (Box 6)
  - Fundraising Reports, 1983 (Box 6)
  - Fusion, 1976-1982; undated (Box 6)
  - "G", 1924-1960; undated (Box 6)
  - Gall, J., 1963-1964; undated (Box 6)
  - Genetic Research, 1972-1976; undated (Box 6)
  - Genetics-Society of America, 1972-1974; undated (Box 6)
  - Gerking Fish Collection, 1973 (Box 6)
  - Gerking, Shelby D., 1946-1955; undated (Box 6)
  - Gier, T. Herschell, 1931-1949 (Box 6)
  - Goals for Employment of Minorities and Women, 1974 (Box 6)
  - Goodrich, Hubert B., 1934-1944 (Box 6)
  - Grading Policy, 1971-1976; undated (Box 6)
  - Grading -"Report on Grades given by instructors, 1913-1914" (Box 6)
  - Graduate (Box 6)
    - Admission, 1969-1978 (Box 6)
    - Council, 1977-1979 (Box 6)
    - Council Meeting Minutes, 1975-1976 (Box 6)
    - Program- Microbiology, 1971-1976; undated (Box 6)
    - School, 1948-1962 (Box 6)
    - Students, 1965-1977 (Box 6)
    - Students-Advisors, 1968-1978 (Box 6)
    - School Council Minutes, 1974-1976 (Box 6)
    - Students-Miscellaneous, 1972-1983 (Box 6)
    - Student Degree Listings of 1887-1965, undated (Box 6)
    - Fellowships (Box 6)
      - 1974-1978 (Box 6)
      - of 1975-1976, 1976-1977 (Box 6)
      - Offer Letters, 2nd Replies of 1977-1978, 1976-1977 (Box 6)
      - of 1978-1979 (Box 6)
      - of 1979-1980 (Box 6)
    - School Bulletin, 1970-1977 (Box 6)
    - School Information, 1962-1968 (Box 6)
    - Student Publications, 1950-1966 (Box 6)
    - Student Listings, 1970-1975 (Box 6)
    - Student Roster, 1949-1976; undated (Box 7)
    - Student Statistics, 1949-1968; undated (Box 7)
    - Students-Support, 1967 (Box 7)
  - Grants, 1972-1981 (Box 7)
  - Grassland Field Research Station, 1970; undated (Box 7)
  - Gross Scholarships-U.School, 1960; undated (Box 7)
  - H-General (Box 7)
    - 1972 (Box 7)
    - 1932-1957, undated (Box 7)
  - Hagen, C.W. Jr.-10 Year Projection of the Division of Biological Sciences, 1964-1965; undated (Box 7)
  - Hazardous Chemicals, 1970-1973; undated (Box 7)
  - Health Professions Committee, 1970-1977 (Box 7)
  - Henn, Arthur-Correspondence, 1914-1933 (Box 7)
  - Herbarium (Box 7)
    - undated (Box 7)
    - Curator, 1961-1972 (Box 7)
  - H.E.W. Title IV Fellowship, undated (Box 7)
  - Holmes, Martin J., 1940-1947 (Box 7)
  - Honorarium, 1950-1964 (Box 7)
  - Honorary Degrees (Glen D. Brown), 1950; undated (Box 7)
  - Honors Division, 1971-1976; undated (Box 7)
  - Human Ecology, 1974 (Box 7)
  - Hunt, Virgil, 1946-1949 (Box 7)
  - I-General, 1949-1955 (Box 7)
  - I-L, 1976-1977; undated (Box 7)
  - Import Permit-Hoboken, NJ, 1961-1972; undated (Box 7)
  - Industrial Contracts, 1973 (Box 7)
  - Institute For Molecular And Cellular Biology, 1982-1984 (Box 7)
  - Institutional Grants, 1960-1964; undated (Box 7)
  - DBS-Instrument Center (Box 7)
    - 1965-1967, undated (Box 7)
    - Budget, 1972-1976 (Box 7)
    - Charges, 1969-1974; undated (Box 7)
  - Instrument Center Committee, 1967-1976; undated (Box 7)
  - Internal Revenue Process, 1980 (Box 7)
  - Internships, 27 Sept 1988 (Box 7)
  - IU Fellowship (Box 7)
    - 1969-1974, undated (Box 7)
    - Info., 1966-1976; undated (Box 7)
  - IU Foundation, 1947-1958; undated (Box 7)
  - IU Medical School Graduate Roster, 1958-1969 (Box 7)
  - IU Water Resources Research Center, 1965 (Box 7)
  - J-General, 1925-1963 (Box 7)
  - Jordan Hall (Box 7)
    - 1955-1966, undated (Box 7)
    - 1967-1968 (Box 7)
    - 1968-1972, undated (Box 7)
    - 1970-1973, undated (Box 7)
    - Additions, 1962-1976, undated (Box 7)
    - Addition Committee, 1968-1969 (Box 7)
    - Addition Committee Minutes, 1966-1968; undated (Box 7)
    - Addition Planning Committee, 1975-1977 (Box 7)
    - Annex, 1958-1968; undated (Box 7)
    - Building Committee Addition Reports, 1975-1976 (Box 8)
    - Calculators/Computers, 1971-1972; undated (Box 8)
    - Plans, 1965-1976; undated (Box 8)
    - Rehabilitation, 1968-1969 (Box 8)
    - Remodeling (Box 8)
      - 1968-1969 (Box 8)
      - 1982 (Box 8)
    - Remodeling and Reports to Space Facil., 1968-1971; undated (Box 8)
    - Security, 1971-1973; undated (Box 8)
    - Space Committee, 1975-1976 (Box 8)
  - K-General, 1925-1955 (Box 8)
  - Kent Farm House, 1982; undated (Box 8)
  - Kinsey, Alfred C. (Box 8)
    - 1932-1955, undated (Box 8)
    - Letters About Kinsey, 1920-1931 (Box 8)
  - Kozloff, Lloyd M., 1970-1974 (Box 8)
  - Kropp, B.N., 1964 (Box 8)
  - Krumholz, Louis A., 1945-1950; undated (Box 8)
  - "L", 1924-1960 (Box 8)
  - L-General, 1974-1977 (Box 8)
  - L100-AT Course, (2nd Semester, 1976-1977) Comments, undated (Box 8)
  - L555 Seminar Series ("Approaches to College Teaching"), 1976 (Box 8)
  - L100-Audio-Tutorial Section, 1970-1972; undated (Box 8)
  - L100(Standard) Course 1977-1978 (Box 8)
  - Lake And Stream Survey, 1953-1954 (Box 8)
  - Language and Tool Skill Requirements (Box 8)
    - 1972 (Box 8)
    - 1970-1977, undated (Box 8)
  - Lauffer, Max A., 1970-1972 (Box 8)
  - Lecture Fund, 1967-1973; undated (Box 8)
  - Library (Box 8)
    - 1947-1955, undated (Box 8)
    - 1970-1976, undated (Box 8)
    - "1969-1975", 1969-1977 (Box 8)
    - DBS, 1970-1975 (Box 8)
    - Committee, 1977-1980 (Box 8)
    - DBS-Library Committee, 1963-1977, undated (Box 8)